Previously on
Space Brothers
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
むった
＜不運に縁がある 兄･六太｡
ひびと
栄光の日生まれの弟･日々人は➡
Born under a lucky star, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker.
日本人初の
ムーンウォーカーとなった｡➡
Older brother Mutta seeks to become an astronaut,
月面望遠鏡建設を望む
恩師･ｼｬﾛﾝとの約束を果たすため➡
and keep his promise to former teacher Sharon, to build a telescope on the moon.
兄･六太は宇宙飛行士を目指す｡➡
Mutta's made it through the first round, but he keeps running into trouble.
選抜試験をかろうじて突破するが
訓練中もトラブルの連続｡➡
On the written test, he scores the lowest.
筆記試験では最低点｡暴走教官が
飛行訓練の担当になる始末｡➡
And as a result, he's assigned to a wild flight instructor.
However, the older brother Mutta has yet to realize that he's rapidly learning
だが 困難にもまれたおかげで
宇宙飛行士の大事な資質を➡
猛スピｰドで身に付けていることに
兄･六太は まだ気付いていない＞
the lessons he'll need to become an astronaut.
(六太)＜あのシャロンが
ＡＬＳと診断された｡➡
Sharon was diagnosed with ALS.
In a few months, she will no longer be able to play the piano anymore.
あと数ヶ月で 大好きなピアノも
弾けなくなってしまう＞
俺が誰より先に選ばれて
月で望遠鏡を立てる予定だよ｡
I plan to be the first one chosen to go to the moon and build your telescope.
＜いち早く宇宙へ行きたい｡
私は教官のヤンじいのもと➡
On my quest to go into space,
I'm now being trained in how to fly the T-38 jet plane by Mr. Young.
ジェット練習機 Ｔ-３８の
飛行訓練を受けている＞
Once the student I'm currently assigned to becomes an official astronaut,
今回 担当する教え子が
宇宙飛行士に認定されたら➡
I'm going to retire...
ワシは引退すると決めとった｡
お前が最後の生徒だ ムッタ｡
You're my last student, Mutta.
(日々人)イエーイ!!
Yay!
＜そして 月面から帰還した
日々人は 会議や講演会のため➡
And after returning from the moon,
Hibito's now going back to Japan for meetings and lectures.
日本に いったん
帰国することになった＞
シャロンのとこにも顔出すよ｡
I'll go see Sharon.
お おう…頼んだ｡
Y-Yeah, I appreciate it.
It's just obvious that the more you put in your bag
The heavier it gets
The harder I work, the closer I get to my goal
But I'm just not getting there fast enough
I gaze at the night sky but it doesn't calm me down
Now that you've heard how loud my heart's beating
Let's take a trip outside
My starvation knows no bounds under this sea of stars
In this planetarium of dreams and reality
I'm currently updating the canvas of my dreams
With a glittering universe and a blue earth
My starvation knows no bounds under this sea of stars
In this planetarium of facades and honesty
I'm currently conversing with the canvas of my dreams
On this orbit of fate
With a fire in my belly
#68 Two Keyboards
あ～ ごめんごめん 間違えた｡
あ～ もっかいいこう！
Oops, sorry... I screwed up. Let's try it again.
Hold on, Hibito...
ちょっと待て 日々人｡お前のｷﾞﾀｰ
ﾁｭｰﾆﾝｸﾞ合ってないんじゃないの？
I think your guitar's out of tune.
(ＣＤ:日々人の声)えっ？そぉ？
Huh? Really?
ＯＫ ヒビト｡音 合ってるわよ｡
さあ もう一回最初からね｡
Okay, Hibito. You're in tune now.
Again, from the top.
おお～っ！ホホホ…｡
いいねえ これ｡
This feels good!
ハァーッ…ハッハー
寝そう…｡
I'm gonna fall asleep.
Oh?
おおっ？なんだ 先客か｡ハハハ…｡
What's this? Someone beat me here?
As I read the latest letter from Sharon,
《新しくきたシャロンからの
手紙を読んで➡
もしかしたら シャロンは少し➡
I got the feeling she'd lost some of her cheer.
元気がないんじゃないかという
気がした》
I'm sure that once I make it to space, Sharon will be thrilled.
《私が宇宙へ行けるとなれば➡
きっとシャロンは
喜んでくれるだろうが➡
But that won't be for a while.
それはまだ 先の話だ》
Right now, is there anything I can do for Sharon?
《今できることで シャロンに
喜んでもらえるようなことは➡
何か あるだろうか…》
(アポ)ワン！
クゥーン…｡
(子供)あぐっ！
Who's next?
(受付)次の方 どうぞ！
あっ…とっとっ…は～い！
い 今 行きま～す！
Yes! Be right there!
よ～っ とっとっ…よいしょっと！
That's a large package...
ずいぶん大きいですね｡
送り先は…日本ですか？
This is headed to Japan?
はい そうです｡お願いします｡
That's right...
Thank you.
お待たせ アポ｡
Sorry for making you wait, Apo.
《フフフ…あんなもんでも➡
I hope this makes Sharon feel a little better.
ちょっとは気晴らしに
なればいいけどな》
いいぞ アポ｡
Let's go, Apo.
ワン！ワンワンワン!!
ワッ！あ～っ…｡
Oh, gosh...
どうしよう…｡
緊張してきた～！
I'm so nervous!
Yay!
イェーイ！
ヤッバイ 似てないって～｡
Girl, that was nothing like him!
(小林)日々人さん 着きましたよ｡
え？…もう？
Hibito, we've arrived.
Huh? Already?
お疲れ様でした｡
It was a long trip.
月に行く時は
全然疲れなかったんだけどな～｡
I was never this tired while traveling to the moon...
Hibito, please put this on.
(小林)日々人さん！
これ かぶっといて下さい｡
Eh? I really have to wear that?
え？ホントにかぶんの？それ｡
(小林)はい！
Yes.
No pushing, please!
くれぐれも押し合わないように
お願いします！➡
He'll be coming out soon!
まもなく来られますので！
ねえ ママ｡
Ｍｒ.ヒビットが来るの？
Hey, Mom... Is Mr. Hibbit gonna be here?
Yep, it's the real Hibbit!
そうよ 本物のヒビットよ！
You don't want to?
(小林)ダメですか？
だって俺 知らねえもんなぁ…➡
Well, I had no idea there was a new fad back home...
こっちで こんなの
流行ってたなんて…｡
Please.
お願いします｡今や日本じゃ
なんば
南波日々人と言えば➡
In Japan, "Nanba Hibito" is synonymous with Mr. Hibbit.
Ｍｒ.ヒビットみたいに
なってるんですから｡ほら｡
Look.
This is such a drag...
《めんどくせえなぁ…➡
I shouldn't have done so much jumping.
あんなにピョンピョン
やらなきゃよかった…》
And we'll need you to deliver your "Yay."
あと 例の｢イェーイ｣も
お願いします｡JAXAのためにも｡
This is for JAXA.
え？どういうこと？
Huh?
What do you mean?
世間もマスコミも み～んな➡
The public and media are looking forward to a live "Yay" from you.
日々人さんの生イェーイが
聞けると期待しています｡
ヤダよ そんなの｡
気分でもないのに わざと言うの｡
When I'm not in the mood, I don't feel like cheering.
っていうか 宇宙飛行士が
帰国第一声で➡
And it seems irresponsible for an astronaut to say "Yay," once he returns home...
｢イェーイ｣なんて
不謹慎だと思うよ｡
Don't worry.
大丈夫｡月面第一声の
｢イェーイ｣の方が数倍不謹慎です｡
Your "Yay" on the moon was much more irresponsible.
うっ…なんと言われようと
ヤなもんはヤですよ！
Y-You can say what you want, but I still don't want to do it!
あっ 来られました！たった今➡
Ah, there he is...
It appears that Nanba Hibito has arrived.
南波日々人さんが
来られた模様です！
≪日々人さ～ん!!≫
≪おかえり～！≫
Hibito!
Welcome home!
Yay!
イェーイ！
ただいま～!!
I'm back!
ご覧下さい｡
日本人初のムーンウォーカー➡
Are you watching this?
Japan's first moonwalker, Nanba Hibito, has just stepped back on Japanese soil!
南波日々人さんが今 母国･日本の
大地に降り立ちました！➡
お帰りなさ～い！
Welcome back!
Breaking News: Astronaut Nanba Hibito has returned!
[TV](ﾚﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)
そして 月面を踏んだ
その両足で 今 まさに今！➡
And the feet which were planted on the surface of the moon are currently treading through Narita Airport!
一歩 また一歩と
ここ成田空港の動く歩道の上を➡
確実に前進しておられます！➡
今日の日々人さんは 黒の
ジャケットにジーンズという➡
Hibito has opted for a casual black jacket and jeans.
カジュアルなコーディネートで
キメています｡
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)おかえり ヒビト｡
Welcome home, Hibito.
Welcome back!
ただいま～｡
なすだ
(茄子田)お久しぶり～｡
I'm back!
Long time, no see.
マジすか…｡
Seriously?
わたくしのこと 覚えてる～？
おかえり 日々人君！
Do you remember me?
Welcome back, Hibito!
つるみ
(鶴見)おかえり 南波君｡
Welcome back, Nanba.
(茄子田)あの ツルミーのは すぐ
ずり落ちちゃうんでね➡
Oh, Tsurumi's kept slipping off...
リャンメンで とめてあんの｡
So we taped it on securely.
では 報告会議を始めます｡
We will now begin the conference.
土曜日の夕方って いいね～｡
ねえ～！
Don't you love Saturday nights?
Yes?
[TV](ﾆｭｰｽの声)日本人初の
ムーンウォーカー➡
On the 5th, Japan's first moonwalker, astronaut Nanba Hibito, participated in his first conference.
南波日々人飛行士は
帰国初日の５日 ＪＡＸＡで➡
第一回目の 報告会議に出席｡
月面での活動について➡
Nanba Hibito
Astronaut
Japan's first moonwalker returns
JAXA Tokyo Branch
He briefed Director Nasuda and other JAXA officials on his moon mission.
茄子田理事長らに
報告をしました｡
Japan's first moonwalker returns
JAXA Tokyo Branch
Nasuda
Director
Astronaut Nanba Hibito
Welcome back!
≪キャー！≫
≪日々人～！≫
Astronaut Nanba Hibito
Welcome back, Astronaut Nanba Hibito!
(ﾚﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)帰国２日目の今日
南波さんは 地元での➡
It's Nanba's second day back,
and he's participating in a hometown parade, greeted by deafening cheers.
がいせん
凱旋パレードに参加され
詰めかけた 多くの人たちの➡
歓声に 応えていらっしゃいます｡
(南波父)天気いいなぁ 今日は｡
Nice weather today...
人も多いなぁ｡こんなに
人がいたのか この街は｡
Lots of people around.
I didn't know there were so many people in this city.
(南波母)あっ お父さん
あそこ見て！ほら！➡
Oh! Look over there, dear!
See? It's Sakurai from 302!
３０２の 桜井さんよ！
Eh?
桜井さ～ん！この間は
わらび餅 ごちそうさま！
Sakurai!
Thanks for the warabimochi you brought us!
すっごく
おいしかったわよ～！
(倉持)≪南波さ～ん！≫
It was delicious!
Nanba!
Oh, Kuramochi!
あ～ら 倉持さん！また
カラオケ行きましょうね！
Let's go to karaoke again sometime!
なあ 母さん｡
Say, dear...
Hmm?
If I shouted "Nyanbo!" right now, would people laugh?
私が 今ここで｢ニャンボ｣を
やったら うけるかな？
Mom and Dad
う～ん そうね…｡
Well...
Mom and Dad
(南波父)《ニャンボ！》
Nyanbo!
いやいや ここは やっぱり…｡
Mom and Dad
No, it'd be better if...
《ニャンボ！》
Nyanbo!
でしょ！
Mom and Dad
Right?
Astronaut
Nanba Hibito's
Children's Lecture
(川上)えっと…上川中学の
川上といいます｡え～と➡
Uh...
I'm Kawakami, from Kamikawa Middle School...
I was wondering how it smells inside a spaceship.
宇宙船の中ってのは いわゆる
その…｢ニオイ｣とか➡
どんな感じなのでしょうか？
あ あ…｡え～っと
上川君 部活は？
A-Ah... Let's see...
Kamikawa, are you in any clubs?
(川上)あ…川上です｡えっと
科学研究部です｡はい｡
Oh, it's Kawakami.
I'm in the science club.
Nice.
なるほど｡じゃあ 今度
サッカー部あたりの部室に➡
Try sneaking into the soccer team's locker room.
こっそり入ってごらんよ｡
宇宙船の中は➡
That's how it smells in a spaceship.
そんな感じの ニオイだよ｡
Okay, thank you very much!
あ はい ありがとうございます！
入ってみます｡
I'll give it a try...
あまり時間がないので
急いでください｡
We're on a tight schedule, so hurry.
わかってるよ｡
Got it.
(ｼｬﾛﾝの声)日々人へ｡その後
調子は どうですか？➡
Dear Hibito,
How have you been doing?
私の方は 以前に比べて 文字が
上手に書けるようになってきた➡
I believe my handwriting is improving.
気がします｡というより 力が
入らない手で 文字を書くコツが➡
It may be more accurate to say that I'm learning to write with a limp hand.
わかってきたと言った方が
正しいのかもしれません｡➡
ただ その代償でしょうか…｡➡
But in return...
いよいよ ピアノを弾くことが
困難になってきたようです｡➡
It's getting more and more difficult to play the piano.
気晴らしに １曲でもと ピアノの
前に座ってみるのですが…｡➡
When I sit down to relax and play a piece,
かつてのピアノとは まるで
別物みたいに 鍵盤は重く➡
the piano has a completely different feel.
The keys are so heavy,
私の指を 押し返してきます｡
my fingers can't hold them down.
(小林)では また２時間後に
迎えにきます｡➡
I'll pick you up in two hours.
急かして すみませんが
総理を待たせるわけには➡
Sorry to rush you, but we can't keep the Prime Minister waiting.
いきませんので…｡
わかってるよ 小林さん｡
ありがとう｡
I know, Kobayashi.
Thanks.
Two hours...
《２時間か…短けぇな》
That isn't much time.
《しょっちゅう替わる
総理大臣より➡
A Prime Minister who's frequently replaced is nowhere near as important to me as she is.
こっちの方が ずっと
大事なんだけどな…》
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)いらっしゃい 日々人｡
忙しいのに➡
Welcome, Hibito.
Thank you for taking time out of your busy schedule.
ありがとう 来てくれて｡
他の用事 すっぽかしてでも
ここには来るよ｡
If necessary, I'd skip everything else to come here.
杖…いつから？
When did you start using that?
Last week.
先週からよ｡でも
買ったのは もっと前｡
But I bought it a while ago.
I happened to come across a cute one.
かわいいの 見つけちゃって｡
ほら この持つところ見て｡
Look at the handle.
中に 宇宙があるのよ｡
You can see space inside!
ほんとだ｡
ねっ！お気に入り｡
You're right.
Yep, I love it.
すいぶん大きな荷物ね｡
何持ってきたの？
That's a big bag.
What did you bring?
これから見せるよ｡
I'm about to show you.
《シャロンまで こんなの
買っちゃって》
Sharon bought one of these, too?
お土産に キーボード
買ってきたんだ｡
I brought you a keyboard as a present.
Huh?
お店の人に 聞いたらさ
ピアノっぽく 鍵盤に➡
I asked at the store...
They said keyboards can either have heavy keys, like pianos, or light keys.
重みがあるタイプと
軽いタイプがあるって｡
で 一番軽くて 一番音がいい
上等なヤツ買ってきた｡
So I got one with the lightest keys and the best sound.
シャロン これで
気晴らしに １曲できるよ｡
Sharon, now...
You can play music to relax.
ありがとう｡
Thank you.
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)ねえ 弾いてみていい？
Say, would you mind if I tried it now?
ああ！何か弾いてよ｡
Sure, play something for us.
わぁ…すごい！
Amazing!
《この兄弟は…
ほんとにすごい！》
Those brothers really are amazing.
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
For Sharon
Give it a try.
Mutta
Thank you,
Thank
Mutta
Thank you, Mutta.
ヘッヘッヘ…
いいもん送ったぜ｡
I picked the right present...
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)いくぞ～
ムッタ！ハハハハ！
Let's go, Mutta!
Yeah.
It's been so long since I looked up at the moon
Though it's always keeping a cold eye on me
Yeah, it always keeps a cold eye on me
I wanna rough up this rotten way home
But even if it makes me mad
I can't take my eyes off it. Yeah, I can't take my eyes off it
I can't take my eyes off that dazzling smile
What did I want back then?
What was I looking for?
I should've known my tears would take me to my dreams
Blow this gloomy reality away for me
I want to see how tiny our huge worries seem
From up in that dark ocean of space
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#69 Next to Hibito
After a frenzy of training, it's finally time for Mr. Young to retire.
＜さまざま忙しい日々を重ねる中
ついに ヤンじいが➡
引退の日を迎える＞
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)＜なあ ムッタ➡
Hey, Mutta...
このラストフライト
離陸から着陸まで➡
On my last flight, I want you to take control from takeoff to landing.
全部 お前がやってくれ＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Next to Hibito"